<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Katarzyna Raciecka - Portfolio</title><link>https://katrac.github.io/katrac/</link><description>Recent content on Katarzyna Raciecka - Portfolio</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://katrac.github.io/katrac/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Scatter Plot - ggplot2</title><link>https://katrac.github.io/katrac/2023/04/scatter-plot-ggplot2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://katrac.github.io/katrac/2023/04/scatter-plot-ggplot2/</guid><description>This is a showcase of using ggplot2 in R to replicate the graph from The Economist showing the relationship between the corruption in countries and the human development index.
Scatter Plot in R using ggplot2
This code shows skills in data analysis and visualization using R, specifically using the ggplot2 package for creating and customizing graphs.
It also shows skills in data manipulation using the data.table package for reading and manipulating data.</description></item><item><title>Absenteeism at work - Machine Learning Model &amp; Tableau</title><link>https://katrac.github.io/katrac/2023/04/absenteeism-at-work-machine-learning-model-tableau/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://katrac.github.io/katrac/2023/04/absenteeism-at-work-machine-learning-model-tableau/</guid><description>Introduction: In this project, I analysed the reasons for excessive absenteeism at work and built a machine learning model in Python to determine the main driver of employee absence. The dataset consisted of 700 observations.
Employees were encouraged to choose one of the categories for reasons for their absence when reporting their absence from work. The categories are as follows:
Reason_1/Group_1: various illnesses, Reason_2/Group_2: pregnancy and childbirth-related, Reason_3/Group_3: poisoning, Reason_4/Group_4: the least serious, such as dental appointments and doctor check-ups.</description></item><item><title>Minesweeper solver</title><link>https://katrac.github.io/katrac/2023/03/minesweeper-solver/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://katrac.github.io/katrac/2023/03/minesweeper-solver/</guid><description>The Minesweeper game solver in Python, where the user chooses the size of the grid and the programme randomly assigns the number of mines. The outcome is a grid with a calculated number of adjacent mines.
Showcasing:
the data structures understanding such as arrays and dictionaries to represent the game board and track the game state, algorithmic thinking to generate and place mines, calculate adjacent mine counts and reveal cells, debugging and error handling, as well as user-centered programming with safeguards and troubleshooting to ensure it functions as intended and handles problems gracefully.</description></item></channel></rss>